Phone: (+64) 22 0780868 Web: https://www.danielballoch.com Email: daniel@thoughtfulhq.com
Github: https://github.com/danielballoch

Daniel Balloch

SKILLS

HTML5, CSS3, styled components, JavaScript, React.js, Gatsby.js, version control, I've also done projects in Next.js and webflow. I've used Node.js (Express/Typescript) for a few projects implementing different APIs from Xero, ActiveCampaign, Snipcart, Stripe to different CMS like Prismic, Contentful, etc, and would love to learn more tools/systems to help businesses. I have some skills in prototyping, design, and editing (adobeXD, photoshop, premiere) and have worked with basic SQL and NoSQL databases (PostgreSQL & MongoDB).

Freelance projects are summarised below and also showcased online at: https://www.danielballoch.com/

EXPERIENCE

Glacier International — Toyota Tundra & Sequoia dealer.

April 2022 - PRESENT

- Web design & development for a 6 page mobile friendly website. For an example of responsive design on the website see the grid setup at the top of the careers page and how this transitions on mobile.
- "Build Your Tundra/Sequoia" pages, which let users select vehicle grade, bed, and colour options, updating vehicle image and price accordingly.
- Order page with automated Xero (accounting software) contact & invoice creation/email. Information is also sent to the Glacier ActiveCampaign account at each stage so the Digital Marketing team at VYNE can follow up with customers.
- Google Places API integrated for address suggestions on the order form.
- Abandoned cart email feature as requested by VYNE Marketing Team.
- Outsourced a small section of Xero API to a friend who was looking for work experience, collaborating on Github. Also worked alongside SEO specialist Matthew from Netbloom, and the digital marketing team at VYNE in the later stages.
- Support form with automated response email via SendGrid.
- Tools: HTML5, CSS3, Gatsby.js, React.js, Node.js, TypeScript, Xero API, ActiveCampaign, SendGrid API, Google Places API.
- Code: https://github.com/danielballoch/GlacierInternational
- Live: https://glacier.nz

Rob Quin — Criminal & Traffic Lawyer

June 2021 - August 2021

- Simple 2 page website redesign with contact form.
- This was a small project helping Rob refresh his web design, making it mobile responsive, and adding a contact form to streamline his workflow.

- Tools: HTML5, CSS3, Gatsby.js, GetForm API.
- Code: https://github.com/danielballoch/RQ
- Live: https://www.robquin.co.nz/

Vanman Logistics - Airport Shuttle & Courier Solutions

March 2021 - January 2022

- Web design & development for 4 page mobile friendly website + CMS.
- 3 stage shuttle booking form using SendGrid API, and with Google Recaptcha integrated for spam protection.
- In person communication with clients Dave & Heather.
- Tools: HTML5, CSS3, Gatsby.js, Node.js, SendGrid API, Prismic CMS.
- Code: https://github.com/danielballoch/Vanman
- Link: https://www.vanman.kiwi/

Raglan Landscape Supplies - Landscape Supplies & Garden Center

April 2022 - May 2022

- This was a small job for a webflow designer. His client wanted a calculator customers could use to figure out how much of a given material they needed before ordering. He designed the website, all I did was code a small calculator section and add pre-existing css styles.
- Tools: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Webflow.
- Link: https://www.raglanlandscapesupplies.co.nz/sand-metal-and-drainage/scoria-7-25mm-drainage-or-decorative

EDUCATION

- · Udemy: The Complete Web Developer in 2020: Zero to Mastery
- Udemy: The Web Developer Bootcamp
- · CompTIA A+ 901
- First Aid Trained
- Red Shirts Customer Service Certificate
- · NCEA Level 3, Hillcrest High School, Hamilton, 2017

AWARDS

- -HHS Video Production Award 2017
- -Distinctions in Digital Technology Essentials (2013) & Programming (2014)
- -Diligence in APE (2017) & Merit endorsement in English (2015)
- -HHS Prem Basketball MVP 2017

Referees

Carlo Meister: Core MMA owner/coach (my gym) and former Team Leader at NetValue for 6+ years.

Malcom King: CEO of Glacier International (most recent client).

Aaron Ross: Former Supervisor at Urgent couriers (Have contracted with Urgent couriers for the past few years as my main income).

-Please contact me if you'd like to arrange a time to phone any referees so I can give you their numbers and give them notice.